Guide to the Francis C. Moon Reuleaux Reference Collection, 1841-2010
Moon, Francis C., Reuleaux Reference Collection
- Series II. Models
  - Other Models
    - Mechanical models: Paris, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 64)
      Articles about collections of mechanical models at the Musee des arts et metiers, Paris. One in french, one in English. Also includes some misc secondary info on Reuleaux.
    - Kinnematik im Tierreiche: articles and Thilo models, 1909-1996 (Box 4, Folder 65)
      Correspondence about Otto Thilo's models based on Reuleaux's Kinnematik im Tierreiche (1909). Also, a secondary article from 1996, and a 1901 article on Reuleaux's K i T.
    - Aachen Photographs, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 66)
      Kinematic models from Prof. Dietrich in Aachen
    - Illinois Gear Collection, Cornell Inventors, 2005 (Box 4, Folder 67)
      Other models. Includes images.
    - Baumann--Moscow St--Models, (n.d.) (Box 4, Folder 68)
      Images of models in Moscow; printed webpages.
    - JBM LdV models, 2002 (Box 4, Folder 69)
      One piece of correspondence about L. da Vinci models at IBM
    - P. Brenni / Florence / Models, 2002-2005 (Box 4, Folder 70)
      Images of Schroeder models at the Institute and Museum of the History of Science, Florence. Correspondence w/ Paolo Brenni and others at the museum. Also includes print-outs from the museum's website.
    - Reuleaux / Aachen visit, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 71)
      Photos and e-mails (photos duplicated elsewhere, but the negatives are here).
    - "Mechanism models" and Reuleaux, 2009 (Box 4, Folder 72)
      "Zur Entwicklungsgeschichte der Getriebemodelle--Ueber die technikgeschichtliche Bedeutung der Getriebe-Prototypen". From the Kolloquium Getriebetechnik, Aachen 2009
    - T.U. Aachen--Models, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 73)
      Includes IGM--Getriebesammlung publication, with a catalog of Aachen's models.
    - U. Porto--Portugal Models, 2003-2004 (Box 4, Folder 74)
      Correspondence, articles, drafts, notes re Porto's model collections (Reuleaux-Voigt).
    - Hauch Collection: Soro, Denmark, (n.d.) (Box 4, Folder 75)
      Fliers and posters
    - S. Shiroshita, Kyoto Musuem. Reuleaux Models: Voigt, Koch, 2000-2001 (Box 4, Folder 76)
      Articles, correspondence
    - F.S.T.--Florence--Models, 2007 (Box 4, Folder 77)
      Correspondence. Listing and images of models. Notes.
    - P. Koch Catalog, 1912 (Box 4, Folder 78)
      Photocopy of Peter Koch's catalog of models
    - Deleuil a Paris, Model makers, 1865-2002 (Box 4, Folder 79)
      Photocopy of instrument catalog from 1865. Relevant bibliography, info on Deleuil. Put together 2002
    - Chemnitz Kinematic Models / Volmer, (n.d.) (Box 4, Folder 80)
      Printed-out images of models, info on Johannes Volmer in Chemnitz and the models
    - Ohio State Models, 2003 (Box 4, Folder 81)
      Printed-out images of models
    - Kyoto--Reuleaux Models, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 82)
    - Riga Models, 2003 (Box 4, Folder 83)
      Photographs, e-mails, article with notes translating
    - Eth-Zurich Models--C. Glocker, 2002 (Box 4, Folder 84)
      E-mail correspondence
    - J. Schubert (1808-1870) Models--Dresden, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 85)
      Article, notes
    - C. Polhem (1661-1751)--Models, 2003 (Box 4, Folder 86)
      Images, photocopied articles, webpage print-outs
    - Modena, 2006 (Box 4, Folder 87)
      One e-mail with links to info on mathematical instruments in Italy
    - Politechnico di Turino models [Schroeder?], 2002 (Box 4, Folder 88)
      Printouts from the webpage of the Politecnico di Torino, about their kinematic models. Includes images
    - Riga / Moll / Reuleaux Models, 2002 (Box 4, Folder 89)
      Images, correspondence re Carl Moll models in Riga
    - Prauge Models -- F. Peterka, 2002 (Box 4, Folder 90)
      Images, correspondence
    - Chebushev Mechanisms, 2002-2003 (Box 4, Folder 91)
      Info on Pafnuty Lvovich Chebyshev. Article, photocopy of a catalog in Russian, images.
    - Asia Model Collections, 2008 (Box 4, Folder 92)
      Article on models in Taiwan, and a CD Rom
    - Non-Cornell models photographs, Undated (Box 2, Folder 61)
    - Rothschild Patent Model Museum, 2005-2006 (Box 2, Folder 75)
- Series III. Moon’s papers and professional work
  Includes drafts and final copies of Moon’s academic papers on Reuleaux and others. Also includes relevant materials for Moon’s lectures and presentations on Reuleaux.
  - Royal Soc. Paper, 2002 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    Correpsondence and drafts for Moon's paper: Robert Willis and Franz Reuleaux: Pioneers in the Theory of Medicine.
  - Franz Reuelaux's small machines, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    Moon article in Cornell's ENGINEERING magazine. Magazine itself rather than a draft or typed copy.
  - 3-D Printing the History of Mechanisms, 2005 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    Paper co-authored by Moon, Hod Lipson, Jimmy Hai, and Carlo Paventi. In the Journal of Mechanical Design, vol 127: Sept 2005 (1029-1033).
  - History of Dynamics of Machines and Mechanisms from Leonardo to Timoshenko, (n.d.) (Box 5, Folder 4)
    Moon paper.
  - Coexisting chaotic and periodic dynamics in clock escapements, 2005-2006 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    Moon paper coauthored with Preston D. Stiefel. *Philosophical Transcriptions of the Royal Society* (2006). 364, 2539-2563. Printed article, plus typed version.
  - Elastic Waves and Solid Armature Contact Pressure in Electromagnetic Launchers, 2006 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    Moon paper coauthored with Anthony J. Johnson. *IEEE Transactions on Magnetics,* Vol 42 No 3. March, 2006. Printed version.
  - Chaotic Clocks and the Use of History of Machines in Mechanics, 2005 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    Moon lecture at the Canadian Congress of Applied Mechanics
  - Franz Reuleaux: Contributions of 19th Century kinematics and theory of machines., 2003 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    Printed copy of Moon Paper. *Applied Mechaniccs Review* vol 56, no 2, March 2003. ASME reprint. Also includes typed version from 2002.
  - The Reuleaux Models: Creating an International Digital Library of Kinematics History, (n.d.) (Box 5, Folder 9)
    Moon article
  - IFToMM report: commission on History of Machines and Mechanisms, 2004 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    A report by Moon.
  - Cornell Association of Professors Emeriti (CAPE): Artifact Collections at CU, 2009 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    "A Compendium of Research and Historical Artifact Collections at Cornell University." Written by Moon. Looks like print-outs of a Power Point
  - The 19th Century Arithmometer of Thomas de Colmar: Inverse Engineering using Kinematic Rapid Prototyping, 2005 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    Draft of Moon paper for IEEE Annals of the History of Computing. Coathored with H. Lipson and T. Kostka.
  - Robert Willis and Franz Reuleaux draft, 2003 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    Typed version of the Willis and Reuleaux paper
  - HMM Papers, 2006 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    Original papers for the History of Machines and Mechanisms conference. Includes lots of powerpoint images.
  - Mathematics Concepts in the Reuleaux Collection of Kinematic Models (Box 5, Folder 45)
    Moon paper
  - Franz Reuleaux: Complexity and Chaos, 2002 (Box 5, Folder 46)
    PowerPoint Slides of a Moon presentation: Franz Reuleaux: Complexity and Chaos in the History of Machines
  - Rx: AMR paper, 2001 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    All correspondence concerning Moon's AMR (*Applied Mechanics Review*) paper.
  - AMR/Rx Final, 2003 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    [AMR files]; Final draft of the paper for AMR. Also includes copy of some of the images for the article.
  - AMR: Reviewer's comments, 2002 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    [AMR files]
  - AMR: Revised Copy, 2002 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    [AMR files] also some correspondence w/ reviewer
  - AMR Paper, 2001 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    Lecture note cards, notes, references list. Research/talks, or maybe stuff Moon produces...
  - AMR/ Rx / Revised, August, 2002 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    Annotated drafts of Moon's paper: "Franz Reuleaux: Contributions to 19th Century Kinematics and Theory of Machines." For Applied Mechanics Reviews.
  - ASME Rx/H and H. Library of Congress., 2003 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    Printed catalog records from Library of Congress; Info on the ASME History and Heritage Committee meeting in D.C., at which Moon presented on Rx.
  - Essays on Rx Collection--F.C.M., 1999-2005 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    Frank Moon articles on Cornell's Rx collection and on Rx.
  - Robert Willis and Franz Reuleaux: Pioneers in the Theory of Machines, 2003 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    Moon's paper for the Royal Society 57(2), 209-230 (2003).
  - Willis/Rx Papers Roy. Soc. 1, 2002 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    [Big blue folder has lots of files on Willis and Rx article Moon published.] Keep together. This one: paperwork and correspondence
  - Willis/Rx Papers Roy. Soc. 2, 2002 (Box 5, Folder 25)
    Draft of paper, CD's with text, high quality images of models, etc.
  - Willis and Rx 3, 2002 (Box 5, Folder 26)
    Correspondence, images, drafts of paper.
  - Willis and Rx / Royal Soc. 4, 2002-2003 (Box 5, Folder 27)
    Correspondence, drafts, an issue of the journal
  - Reuleaux: Misc, Kennedy, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 28)
    Draft of Moon's the Cornell Reuleaux Collection of Mechanisms
  - Reuleaux Triangle, 2000 (Box 5, Folder 29)
    Draft 3 of Moon paper: Reuleaux Triangles and Rollers: Models in the Cornell Kinematics Collection
  - Articles: Triangles, Rotary (Box 5, Folder 30)
    Articles for Moon's research on rollers, rotary, Rx triangles
  - Triangles and Rollers: drafts and notes, 2000 (Box 5, Folder 31)
    Drafts 1 and 2 of Moon paper: Draft 3 of Moon paper: Reuleaux Triangles and Rollers: Models in the Cornell Kinematics Collection. Also, relevant notes
  - Rx Triangles, 2000-2003 (Box 5, Folder 32)
    More notes, more drafts. Includes draft 4 of above, and a draft of Moon's The Reuleaux Triangle and Constant Width Rollers: Models in the Cornell Kinematic Collection
  - Reuleaux Triangle/Rollers, Wankel Engines, 1999-2000 (Box 5, Folder 33)
    Notes, research, drafts. Includes draft of Moon paper: Franz Reuleaux: The Man Who Deconstructed the Machine.
  - Reuleaux Triangles and Rollers: Models in the Cornell Kinematic Collection, 2000 (Box 5, Folder 34)
    Handwritten drafts of Moon's article
  - Reuleaux: Book Proposal/outline, 1999-2002 (Box 5, Folder 35)
    Correspondence, drafts of the book proposal
  - Reuleaux: Book Proposal Final, 2002 (Box 5, Folder 36)
    Final draft of the book proposal
  - Reuleaux: Bookpress Article, 1999-2000 (Box 5, Folder 37)
    Drafts of Moon article: "Franz Reuleaux: The man who deconstructed the machine." Also includes a floppy disk.
  - Reuleaux article, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 38)
    Franz Reuleaux's small machines. Looks like it's from some Cornell publication.
  - Bookpress--Paper on Rx, Feb 2000 (Box 5, Folder 39)
    Newspaper
  - Moon Rx articles, 1999-2000 (Box 5, Folder 40)
    Includes "The Cornell Reuleaux Collection of Mechanisms," "The Reauleaux Collection of Mechanisms at Cornell University," and Franz Reauleaux: "19th Century History of Kinematics and History of Machines."
  - Leonardo Da Vinci and Reuleaux, 2003 (Box 5, Folder 41)
    Overhead projections on Leonardo Da Vinci and Reuleaux from Moon lectures
  - F.C. Moon: Lectures on Reuleaux, 2003 (Box 5, Folder 42)
    Lists of lectures, and fliers
  - F.C. Moon Lecture: "Light in Winter" Dance of the Machines, 2005 (Box 5, Folder 43)
    Lecture outline and narration
  - F.C. Moon Rx Publ, 2002-2004 (Box 5, Folder 44)
    Moon papers, re Rx models, KMODDL, etc.
  - IFToMM Workshop-Lectures: History of Machines and Mechanisms, 2006 (Box 7)
    Includes a schedule for the conference at Cornell, and a Moon-edited publication of relevant papers. IFToMM stands for International Federation for the Theory of Machanisms and Machines. [OVERSIZE / LEGAL SIZE]
  - ASEE Prism, 2004 (Box 2, Folder 69)
- Series IV. Multimedia and Photographs
  Includes images of model collections, many of which were for the KMODDL project. They include photographs taken of models at the Deutsches Museum and Karlsruhe, and original slides of images of Cornell’s Reuleaux models. Additional formats include CD’s, floppy disks, and printouts.
  - Images: Karlsruhe Models, (n.d.) (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Cornell Model images printouts, (n.d.) (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Cornell Model images 1, (n.d.) (Box 6, Folder 3)
    printed in color on glossy paper
  - Cornell Model images 2, (n.d.) (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Cornell Model images 3, (n.d.) (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Cornell Model images 4, (n.d.) (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Deutsches Museum: Model images, (n.d.) (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Slides: Cornell Rx for KMODDL, (n.d.) (Box 6, Folder 8)
    original slides, Moon esp. concerned
  - Envelope 1 (Saturn) Model Photos, 2001 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    [set of 6 envelopes with pictures. Also include negatives]. Pictures of models from the Deutsches Museum in Munich.
  - Envelope 2 (Saturn) Model Photos, 2001 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Envelope 3 (Saturn) Model Photos, 2001 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    Just negatives
  - Envelope 4 (Saturn) Model Photos, 2001 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Envelope 5 (white) Model Photos, 2001 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    Mixture of DM models and Rx landmarks
  - Envelope 6 (white) Model Photos, 2001 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Karlsruhe Models Redtenbacher (ZIP), 2002 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Hannover Models (Folder); Cornell Models. (ZIP), 2002 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Germany. Rx/German-American; Redtenbacher Bro (ZIP), 2002 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    Title further reads London Sci Museum 1876 Int'l Exhibition Rx Models Photos. Cambridge Univ R. Willis Sketches and Drawings.
  - Reuleaux Book/Misc; Rx Catalog/Models (ZIP), 2001 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Deutsches Museum Models (ZIP), 2001 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    Includes a list on the outside. Seems to include Karlsruhe Models and Hannover Models as well.; Zip Drive Instruction Manual
  - Kyoto Rx Models 1 (Envelope w/ 5 floppy disks) (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Kyoto Rx Models 2 (Envelope w/ 4 floppy disks) (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Kyoto Rx Models 3 (Envelope w/ 4 floppy disks) (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Reuleaux Brochure (loose ZIP), 2001 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Floppy Backups: Munich, Dresden, Karlsruhe, Hannover, 2001 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - CD: Dresden Models (Box 6, Folder 25)
    PA190015.JPG--PA190053.JPG
  - CD: Deutsches Museum Reuleaux Models, 2001 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - CD: Dresden: Schubert Models (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - CD: Rx/Clock Lecture PowerPoint (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - CD: Moon's talk: Machine pictures (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Rothschild Patent Model Collection Photos #1, Undated; CD-3911
  - Rothschild Patent Model Collection Photos #2, Undated; CD-3912
  - Rothschild Patent Model Collection Photos #3, Undated; CD-3913
  - Rothschild Patent Model Collection Photos #4, Undated; CD-3914
  - Rothschild Patent Model Collection Photos #5, Undated; CD-3915
  - John Syalor Homer speech, Undated; CD-3916
  - Museum project, Undated; CD-3917
  - Explore Cornell: A Digital Library of Kinematics K-MODDL, Undated; CD-3918
  - Media and photo notes, 2000-2002 (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - Explore Cornell: K-MODDL Reaucellier and Slider Crank, QTVRS and videos, 2002-03-07; CD-3919
  - Project: Cornell University Engineering Dept. - Reuleaux A01-E04, 2002-03-07; CD-3920
  - Project: Cornell University Engineering Dept. - Reuleaux E05-M02, 2002-03-07; CD-3921
  - Project: Cornell University Engineering Dept. - Reuleaux M04-O01, 2002-03-07; CD-3922 (Box 2)
  - Project: Cornell University Engineering Dept. - Reuleaux O02-S07, 2002-03-07; CD-3923 (Box 2)
  - Project: Cornell University Engineering Dept. - Reuleaux S08-S37, 2002-03-07; CD-3924 (Box 2)
  - Project: Cornell University Engineering Dept. - Reuleaux S38-V13, 2002-03-07; CD-3925 (Box 6)
  - Project: Cornell University Engineering Dept. - Reuleaux V14-Y05, 2002-03-07; CD-3926 (Box 6)
  - Project: Cornell University Engineering Dept. - Reuleaux Y06-Z07, 2002-03-07; CD-3927 (Box 6)
  - Reuleaux basic files, Undated; CD-3928
  - Dell Cpt product recovery, Dell Cpt Win 98se, Undated; CD-3929
  - Win 98 2nd Ed., Undated; CD-3930
  - Untitled, Undated; CD-3931
  - Untitled, Undated; CD-3932
  - Untitled, Undated; CD-3933
  - Clark I, Undated; DVD-2672
  - Untitled, Undated; TR-17135 (Box 7)
  - Reuleaux Models, F. Moon Cornell, 2001; V-10707 (Box 7)
  - Untitled, Undated; FD-724
  - Untitled, Undated; ZD-83
  - Untitled, Undated; ZD-84
  - Rx 3D Printed Models - Model Descriptions, 2002-11; ZD-85
  - F. Moon paper on R. Willis and F. Reuleaux, text plus figures file, 2002-10; ZD-86
  - F. Reuleaux: Contributions to 19th C. Kinematics and Theory of Machines, 2002-08; ZD-87
    To appear in Applied Mechanics Review, 2003.
  - Jon Reis Reuleaux slides, 1999 (Box 7, Folder 1)